<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alejandro Yopasá Arenas</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alejandro Yopasá Arenas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Predição do Desvio Padrão Relativo da reprodutibilidade (PRSD (R)), ou Trompete de Horwitz</title>
      <link>/post/2020-10-24-r-rmarkdown-horw-pt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-10-24-r-rmarkdown-horw-pt/</guid>
      <description>Predição do Desvio Padrão Relativo da reprodutibilidade (PRSD (R)), ou “Trompete de Horwitz””.Com base nos resultados de milhares de estudos de desempenho de métodos interlaboratoriais, o Dr. William Horwitz calculou as estimativas dos desvios padrão de repetibilidade e reprodutibilidade (entre laboratórios). Ele notou que à medida que a concentração do analito diminuía em duas ordens de magnitude, o desvio padrão relativo da reprodutibilidade (RSDR) aumentava por um fator de dois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicted relative standard deviation of the reproducibility (PRSD(R)), the “Horwitz Trumpet</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Predicted relative standard deviation of the reproducibility (PRSD(R)), the “Horwitz Trumpet”.Based on the results of thousands of interlaboratory method performance studies, Dr William Horwitz calculates the estimates of the repeatability and reproducibility (between laboratory) standard deviations. He noticed that as the concentration of the analyte decreased over two orders of magnitude, the relative standard deviation of reproducibility (RSDR) increased by a factor of two. This pattern persisted at least down to sub-ppm levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferramentas de trabalho</title>
      <link>/post/rstudio-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rstudio-r/</guid>
      <description>Guia básico de R, RStudio e RMarkdown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Create a beautifully simple website in under 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
